freshdesk.com 2017-06-06

# Help desk and customer support software - Privacy policy Freshdesk

**Effective Date**  
October 31, 2016

Freshdesk Inc. (“Freshdesk”) is committed to protecting your privacy. This Privacy Policy (“Policy”) applies to those who visit the Websites owned and operated by Freshdesk, as well as users of our Service(s). This Privacy Policy describes how Freshdesk collects, uses, shares and secures the personal information you provide. It also describes your choices regarding use, access and correction of your personal information. The use of information collected through our Service(s) shall be limited to the purpose of providing the service for which the Customer has engaged Freshdesk. The capitalized terms used in this Policy but not defined herein shall have the same meaning as defined in our Terms of Service at Freshdesk.com/terms (“Terms”).

If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at [support@freshdesk.com](mailto:support@freshdesk.com).

##### **EU-US Privacy Shield Compliance**

Freshdesk Inc. participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. Freshdesk Inc. is committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield List [<https://www.privacyshield.gov/list>]. 

Freshdesk Inc. is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under the Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. Freshdesk Inc. complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, Freshdesk Inc. is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, Freshdesk Inc. may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website [[https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to- Submit-a-Complaint](https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint)], you may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

##### US-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework Compliance

Freshdesk Inc. complies with the U.S. – Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use and retention of personal data from Switzerland. Freshdesk Inc. has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Freshdesk Inc.’s certification, please visit <https://safeharbor.export.gov/swisslist.aspx>.

##### How Do We Collect, Use and Share Your Personal Information and Other Information?

**Collection**

We may collect the following personal information from you within the Websites:

  * Contact Information, such as name, email address, mailing address, or phone number;
  * Information about your business, such as company name, company size, business type

We may collect the following personal information from you when you use our Service(s):

  * Contact Information, such as name, email address, mailing address, IP address, geographic location, or phone number;
  * Billing Information, such as credit card number and billing address;
  * Unique Identifiers, such as username, account number or password;
  * Name and e-mail address when you provide feedback from the Service(s)

For Glowboard and Freshsales, in addition to the above, the following personal information about your contacts is collected from you:

  * We collect your e-mail address through the Website in order to refer our Service(s).

For Freshsales, in addition to the above, the following personal information about your contacts is collected from you:

  * In order to manage customer relationships, our customers may collect name, e-mail address, phone number, physical address, billing information, designation, company name of your contacts through the “import contacts” feature within the Service.

**Use**

We may use the personal information collected from within the Websites or when you use the Service(s) to:

  * Provide you with the Service(s).
  * Send you communication from the Service(s).
  * Assess the needs of your business to determine or suggest suitable products
  * Send you requested product or service information
  * Respond to customer service requests
  * Administer your account
  * Send you promotional and marketing communications
  * Respond to your questions and concerns
  * Facilitate your transactions with other users when you use our Service(s).

When you provide us with personal information about your contacts we will only use this information for the specific reason for which it is provided. 

Except as outlined in this Policy, your information will never be sold to or shared with other companies or organizations for commercial purposes or otherwise. We may transfer personal information to our Group Companies and sub-contractors that help us provide our Service(s). Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the service agreements with our sub-contractors. Such sub-contractors may include third-party payment processors who process your credit card and other payment information for Freshdesk but are otherwise not permitted to store, retain or use such information.

##### Correction or Removal of Personal Information

If you believe that one of your contacts has provided us with your personal information and you would like to request that it be removed from our database, please contact us at [support@freshdesk.com](mailto:support@freshdesk.com)

Freshdesk collects information on behalf of our customers, and has no direct relationship with the individuals with whom our customers may interact using the Service(s). If you are a customer of one of our customers (“End-Customer”) and would no longer like to be contacted by that customer, please contact the customer that you interact with directly. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data should direct his query to the Freshdesk’s customer (the data controller). If requested to remove data, we will respond within a reasonable timeframe.

##### Other Information

Other information such as End-Customer device models, IP address, usage patterns are also captured by the Service(s). This information is not used by Freshdesk except in allowing you to view and use this information for targeting future communication with the End-Customers. Content and messages in voice, text or other format created by you or your End-Customers to send or share with other users or End-Customers shall be hosted on Freshdesk’s servers.

##### Retention of Personal Information

We retain Personal Data we process for as long as an Account is active or as needed to provide the Service(s). If you wish to terminate your Account or request that we no longer use Your Data, please contact us at [support@freshdesk.com](mailto:support@freshdesk.com). We will retain Your Data as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, maintain accurate financial and other records, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. We delete all Your Data on the expiry of 14 days after the termination of your Account, except as otherwise prohibited by applicable law.

##### Processing Personal Information

We are the data processors and not the data controllers of the information on our platform for purposes of the EU Directive on Data Protection (Directive) and the Swiss Federal Act on Data Protection. Our EEA or Switzerland based customers, who control their customer data and send it to Freshdesk for processing, are the “controllers” of that data and are responsible for compliance with the Directive. In particular, Freshdesk’s customers are responsible for complying with the Directive and relevant data protection legislation in the relevant EEA member state before sending personal information to Freshdesk for processing. We work with our customers to help them provide notice to their customers concerning the purpose for which personal information is collected.

We store and process data, including personal information, in the United States and the European Economic Area (“EEA”) and possibly in other countries through third parties that we use to operate and manage the Service(s). When you access or use our Websites or the Service(s), or otherwise provide information to us, you are consenting, on behalf of you and your authorized agents or End-Customers, (and representing that you have the authority to provide such consent) to the processing and transfer of information in and to the United States and other countries which may have different privacy laws from your or their country of residence. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Policy. We may enter agreements with our customers located in the EEA to provide them access to our Service(s), which includes the processing of information relating the End-Customers.

We do not own, control or direct the use of the information stored or processed on our platform, and in fact we are largely unaware of what information is being stored on our platform and only access such information as reasonably necessary to provide the Service(s) (including to respond to support requests), as otherwise authorized by our customers or as required by law.

It shall be our customers’ responsibility to inform the End-Customers about and obtain necessary consent for any personal information that is collected through our customer’s use of the Service(s). As the processors of personal information on behalf of our customers, we follow their instructions with respect to the information they control to the extent consistent with the functionality of our Service(s). In doing so, we implement technical, physical and administrative measures against unauthorized processing of such information and against loss, destruction of, or damage to, personal information as more fully described under the section below entitled, “Protection of Information”.

##### Mobile Applications

When you download, install and use our Mobile Applications, we automatically collect information on the type of device you use, operating system version, and the device identifier (or “UDID”).

We send you push notifications from time-to-time in order to update you about any events or promotions that we may be running. If you no longer wish to receive these types of communications, you may turn them off at the device level. To ensure you receive proper notifications, we will need to collect certain information about your device such as operating system and user identification information.

We use mobile analytics software to allow us to better understand the functionality of our Mobile Application on your mobile or handheld device. This Mobile Application may record information such as how often you use the Mobile Application, the events that occur within the Mobile Application, aggregated usage, performance data, and where the Mobile Application was downloaded from. We do not link the information we store within the analytics software to any personally identifiable information you submit within the Mobile Application.

##### Analytics

Freshdesk uses third party software for analytics. All metrics information collected from your usage of the Service(s) shall be transmitted to analytics provider. This information is then used to evaluate how users use Freshdesk, and to compile statistical reports on activity for us. We further use the same statistical analytics tool to track or to collect your Personally Identifiable Information (PII). We will use this information in order to maintain, enhance, or add to the functionality of the Service(s) and to personalize the experience for you. Anonymized and aggregated information and analysis may be made public where desired by Freshdesk. Third party analytics software will not share your PII or associate your PII with any other data held by them.

##### Use of Cookies

When you use our Websites or Service(s), we may store some information on your computer. This information will be in the form of a “cookie” or similar file. Cookies are small pieces of information stored on your hard drive, not on the Freshdesk website. We do not use cookies to spy on you or otherwise invade your privacy. They cannot invade your hard drive and steal information. We use cookies to help you navigate the Websites and Service(s) as easily as possible, and to remember information about your current session. These are the Session Cookies and they are removed from your system when you close the web browser or turn off the computer. You must enable cookies on your web browser to use the Service(s).

We use Local Shared Objects, such as Flash cookies, and Local Storage, such as HTML5, to store content information and preferences. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our Websites or to display advertising based upon your web browsing activity also use Flash cookies or HTML5 to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5.

To manage Flash cookies, please click here: <http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html>

**Essential Cookies:** These cookies are essential for the basic functionalities offered by the Service(s). These class of cookies helps in keeping a user logged in to the Service(s) and remember relevant information when they return to the Service(s). These cookies are essential for the basic functionalities offered by the Service(s). These class of cookies helps in keeping a user logged in to the Service(s) and remember relevant information when they return to the Service(s).

**Insight Cookies:** These are used for tracking the user activities within the Service(s), which in turn helps us in improving your user experience.

**Marketing Cookies:** These are used for providing you with customized and interest-based ads based on your browsing behavior and other similar activities on our Websites.

##### List of Cookies

The cookies (our own and third party) we may use in connection with our Websites and the Service(s) provided are:

**List of cookies used by the Services:**

Cookie Name  |  Purpose  |  Service using the Cookies  |  Privacy Policy   
---|---|---|---  
contacts_sort | To persist the contact page filter choice | Freshdesk | <https://freshdesk.com/privacy>  
scenario_show_tab | To persist the scenario automation visibility tab(shared/personal) | Freshdesk | <https://freshdesk.com/privacy>  
tag_sort_key | Persist the tag management sort key in index page | Freshdesk | <https://freshdesk.com/privacy>  
search_sort | Persist the sort value in search page | Freshdesk | <https://freshdesk.com/privacy>  
fd_mobile_email | Get google auth token and use it on future requests for native mobile | Freshdesk | <https://freshdesk.com/privacy>  
mobile_access_token | This is used to get user api token | Freshdesk | <https://freshdesk.com/privacy>  
helpdesk_url | Setting domain of the account | Freshdesk | <https://freshdesk.com/privacy>  
filter_name | Ticket filter name for agent | Freshdesk | <https://freshdesk.com/privacy>  
sort_order | Persist ticket view sort order | Freshdesk | <https://freshdesk.com/privacy>  
helpdesk_node_session | setting node session of the generated hash | Freshdesk   
Freshservice | <https://freshdesk.com/privacy>  
current_wf_order | Used to store order of filter | Freshdesk | <https://freshdesk.com/privacy>  
current_wf_order_type | Used to store order type of ticket filter | Freshdesk | <https://freshdesk.com/privacy>  
_fcata | This is the authentication cookie we use for tracking user (our product customer) login and logout. | Freshchat | <https://freshdesk.com/privacy>  
_fccs | This is a dummy cookie used for tracking whether the user(our product customer) is logged in or logged out for UI purpose. | Freshchat | <https://freshdesk.com/privacy>  
_fcvd | This is used to track the freshchat domains the agent/user (our product customer) logged/signed into so we can use this for improving the login/signup experience. | Freshchat  
Freshsales | <https://freshdesk.com/privacy>  
_session_id | This is used for maintaining the user session. | Freshchat  
Freshcaller | <https://freshdesk.com/privacy>  
rack.session | This is used for maintaining the user session. | Freshchat | <https://freshdesk.com/privacy>  
_fcatv | This is the authentication cookie with which we authenticate/authorize the visitor uniquely. | Freshchat | <https://freshdesk.com/privacy>  
_fc_unq | Unique id used to identify the visitor. | Freshchat | <https://freshdesk.com/privacy>  
_fc_vname | Name of the visitor (provided by visitor) | Freshchat | <https://freshdesk.com/privacy>  
SRF-TOKEN | To prevent Cross-Site Request Forgery | Hotline | <https://freshdesk.com/privacy>  
Auth | To uniquely identify logged-in in user | Hotline | <https://freshdesk.com/privacy>  
App | To uniquely identify account | Hotline | <https://freshdesk.com/privacy>  
push_notif | To uniquely identify endpoint(device) to send push notification | Hotline | <https://freshdesk.com/privacy>  
_helpkit_session | To maintain user session | Freshservice  
Freshsales | <https://freshdesk.com/privacy>  
user_credentials | To login a user | Freshservice | <https://freshdesk.com/privacy>  
filter_name | List page filters state maintenance | Freshservice | <https://freshdesk.com/privacy>  
wf_order | Ticket list page filter sort | Freshservice | <https://freshdesk.com/privacy>  
wf_order_type | Ticket list page filter sort type(Asc/Desc) | Freshservice | <https://freshdesk.com/privacy>  
ticket_view_choice | To list old and new ticket details | Freshservice | [https://freshdesk.com/privacy](https://freshdes.com/privacy)  
ticket-filter-closed | Slider open, close state for ticket list page | Freshservice | <https://freshdesk.com/privacy>  
cmdb-filter-closed | Slider open, close state for cmdb list page | Freshservice | <https://freshdesk.com/privacy>  
problem-filter-closed | Slider open, close state for problem list page | Freshservice | <https://freshdesk.com/privacy>  
release-filter-closed | Slider open, close state for release list page | Freshservice | <https://freshdesk.com/privacy>  
Inspectlet | Discover where visitors are getting confused on your app and what's getting their attention. | Glowboard | <https://www.inspectlet.com/legal>  
_x_w | Used in support.freshsales.io | Freshsales | https://freshdesk.com/privacy  
_x_m | Used in support.freshsales.io | Freshsales | https://freshdesk.com/privacy  
_freshsales_session | To maintain user session | Freshsales | https://freshdesk.com/privacy  
auth_token | Authentication token for the session | Freshsales | https://freshdesk.com/privacy  
fs_analytics_visitor | To track Website visitors | Freshsales | https://freshdesk.com/privacy  
fcs | To identify if the user is authenticated in client | Freshcaller | https://freshdesk.com/privacy  
_fs | Authentication cookie to check if user is authenticated | Freshcaller | https://freshdesk.com/privacy  
  
**List of cookies used by the Websites**

Set by or   
on behalf of | Purpose | Websites using the cookies | Privacy Policy  
---|---|---|---  
Google analytics | Website analytics cookie for visitor information and source. | Freshdesk  
Hotline  
Freshsales  
Freshservice  
Freshchat  
Glowboard  
Freshcaller | <http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>  
Adwords Conversion | Conversion tracking cookie for ads delivered by Google Adwords | Freshdesk  
Freshsales  
Freshservice  
Freshchat  
Glowboard | <http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>  
Google Interest-based ads | Cookie to serve ads based on a user’s prior visits to our website. | Freshservice  
Freshchat  
Glowboard | <http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>  
Capterra | Conversion tracking cookie for ads delivered by Capterra | Freshdesk  
Freshsales  
Freshservice  
Freshchat | <http://www.capterra.com/legal_privacy_policy>  
Facebook | Facebook tracking to track people interactions with the Like button. | Freshdesk  
Freshsales  
Freshservice Freshchat | <http://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/>  
Importing reviews from Facebook onto Glowboard. | Glowboard  
Criteo | Track information about which pages you viewed, and in certain cases which products you bought. | Freshdesk  
Freshservice | <http://www.criteo.com/privacy/>  
Doubleclick | Service for accessing multiple sources of online display advertising inventory. | Freshdesk  
Freshservice | <http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>  
Getapp | Getapp partners with third party ad networks to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. | Freshdesk  
Freshsales  
Freshservice Freshchat | <https://www.getapp.com/privacy_policy>  
Acquisio | Acquisio uses third parties to assist us in measuring statistical information about users of the Service(s). | Freshdesk | <http://www.acquisio.com/privacy-policy>  
Chango | User data tracking to deliver consumers more relevant advertising. | Freshdesk  
Freshservice | <https://www.chango.com/privacy/policy/>  
Quantcast | QuantCast cookies collect data for the purpose of interest-based advertising. | Freshdesk  
Freshservice | <http://www.quantcast.com/how-we-do-it/consumer-choice/privacy-policy/>  
Bing | Used to track the pages you view and links you click when using Microsoft's and its advertising partners' web sites and services. | Freshdesk  
Freshsales  
Freshservice  
Freshchat  
Glowboard | <http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/privacystatement/default.aspx>  
Magnetic | A unique, random identifier to anonymously track users for targeted advertising. | Freshdesk  
Freshservice  
Glowboard | <http://www.magnetic.com/privacy/corporate-privacy-policy/>  
Shareasale | A third party affiliate marketing network. | Freshdesk  
Freshservice | <https://www.shareasale.com/agreement.cfm>  
<https://www.shareasale.com/w3c/policy.html>  
Bizible | A plug-in that brings marketing and sales data together. | Freshdesk  
Freshservice  
Glowboard | <http://www.bizible.com/privacy-policy>  
Linkedin | LinkedIn cookies for the purpose of interest-based advertising. | Freshdesk  
Freshservice  
Glowboard | <http://www.linkedin.com/legal/cookie_policy>  
Zarget | Website optimization and A/B testing tool | Freshdesk  
Freshservice  
Freshsales | <https://zarget.com/privacy-policy.html>  
helpdesk_auth_url | To log users into Freshdesk's Developer portal. | Freshdesk | <https://freshdesk.com/privacy>  
Mixpanel | Website analytics cookie for visitor information and source | Freshservice  
Glowboard | <https://mixpanel.com/privacy/>  
Heap analytics | Website analytics cookie for visitor information and source | Hotline  
Freshchat  
Glowboard  
Freshsales | <https://heapanalytics.com/privacy>  
TrackJS | Tracks the errors that occur in user’s browser | Freshsales | <https://trackjs.com/privacy/>  
New Relic | Track the rendering time | Freshsales  
Freshchat | <https://newrelic.com/privacy>  
Segment | Tracks the customer’s activities within the Service(s) | Freshsales  
Freshchat  
Freshservice | <https://segment.com/docs/legal/privacy/>  
Freshsales | Tracks the customer’s activities within the Service(s) | Freshsales  
Freshchat  
Freshservice | <https://freshdesk.com/privacy>  
Freshchat | Tracks authentication, and website cookies. | Freshchat | <https://freshdesk.com/privacy>  
Freshdesk | Tracks the customer’s activities within the Service(s) | Freshservice | <https://freshdesk.com/privacy>  
Kissmetrics | Website analytics cookie for visitor information and source | Freshdesk | <https://www.kissmetrics.com/privacy/>  
Optimizely | Website optimization and A/B testing tool | Hotline  
Freshservice  
Glowboard | <https://www.optimizely.com/privacy/>  
Hotjar | Video Recording and Heatmap testing tool | Freshservice  
Freshchat  
Glowboard  
Freshsales | <https://www.hotjar.com/privacy>  
leadforensics | Tool to identify website visitor location using IP tracking | Freshservice | <http://www.leadforensics.com/privacy-and-cookies/>  
Twitter | Twitter tracking to track people interactions. | Freshservice | <https://twitter.com/privacy>  
Wistia | Embedding interactive videos on our website and measuring engagement | Freshservice | <https://wistia.com/privacy>  
Autopilot | Track information about which pages you visited and capture the form information | Freshchat  
Freshservice  
Glowboard | <https://autopilothq.com/privacypolicy.html>  
Clickmeter - Finances Online Conversion (GTM) | Conversion tracking cookie for ads delivered by Clickmeter | Freshservice | <https://financesonline.com/privacy-policy/>  
pnctest | To maintain a connection to the user while they are using Freshchat | Freshchat  
Freshsales | https://freshdesk.com/privacy  
__distillery | Tracking of video from Wistia | Freshsales | https://wistia.com/privacy  
muxData | Set by Wistia | Freshsales | https://wistia.com/privacy  
fd_flu | First Landing URL | Freshdesk  
Freshservice  
Hotline  
Freshsales  
Freshchat  
Freshcaller | https://freshdesk.com/privacy  
fd_fr | First Referrer from which site/ad page is loaded | Freshdesk  
Freshservice  
Hotline  
Freshsales  
Freshchat  
Freshcaller |   
fd_se | From which Search Engine the page is loaded | Freshsales | https://freshdesk.com/privacy  
fd_sq | From what query the page is loaded | Freshsales | https://freshdesk.com/privacy  
first_session | Info of search engine, url, visits, last page visit, etc. | Freshsales | https://freshdesk.com/privacy  
maxmind_location_v1  
maxmind_location | User location during signup | Freshsales | https://freshdesk.com/privacy  
__attsc | Related with sharing the page in Facebook | Freshsales | https://freshdesk.com/privacy  
_-atuvc | To enable the visitors to share the page in Facebook. Stores the page share count | Freshsales | https://freshdesk.com/privacy  
smToken | Used by third party provider to identify the user uniquely | Freshsales | https://freshdesk.com/privacy  
_dc_gtm_* | It is used to add tracking code from Google Tag Manager | Freshsales | http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/  
disqus_unique | Used by Disqus plugin | All pages containing Disqus plugin | https://help.disqus.com/customer/portal/articles/466259-privacy-policy  
  
You can set your browser to either reject all cookies, to allow only “trusted” websites to set them, or to accept only those cookies from those websites you are currently on.

For more information on controlling cookie settings in your browser, please refer to the following links:

More information on ["Incognito" mode and cookie setting in Google Chrome](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95464?hl=en)  
More information on ["InPrivate" and cookie setting in Internet Explorer](https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/products/windows)  
More information on ["Private Browsing" and cookie setting in FireFox](http://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/settings-privacy-browsing-history-do-not-track)  
More information on ["Private Browsing" and cookies setting in Safari](http://support.apple.com/kb/ht1677)  

Please note that if you wish to turn off the cookies in your web browser, you might not be able to take advantage of many features of our Service(s).

To learn how to delete or disable cookies in general, visit [www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies.](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/)

Freshdesk customers have the responsibility to inform the individuals with whom they interact with via the help of the Service(s) about the cookies used by Freshdesk and by themselves and should obtain individuals’ consent, if necessary.

##### Clear Gifs and Log Files

We and our third party advertising partners use technologies such as web beacons in analyzing trends, administering the website, tracking users’ movements around the site, and gathering demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual and aggregated basis.

As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We link this automatically collected data to other information we collect about you.

Do Not Track. Do Not Track (“DNT”) is an optional browser setting that allows you to express your preferences regarding tracking by advertisers and other third parties. We do not use technology that recognizes DNT signals from your web browser.

We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our Websites or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this Website and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by [clicking here](https://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) (or if located in the European Union, [click here](https://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)). Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads.

##### Social Media Features

Our Websites includes social media features, such as the Facebook “Like” button, the “Share This” button or interactive mini-programs. Where we have your consent, these features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our Websites, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Websites. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing them.

##### Links to Third Party Sites

Our Websites contain links to other websites that are not owned or controlled by Freshdesk. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other websites or third parties. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our Websites and to read the privacy policies of each and every website that collects personal information.

##### Public Forums

Our Websites offer publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at [support@freshdesk.com](mailto:support@freshdesk.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know that we are unable to do so and why.

##### Single Sign-On

You can log in to our Websites using sign-in services such as Google, Facebook Connect. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and email address. Services like Google, Facebook Connect give you the option to post information about your activities on our Websites to your profile page and to share information with others within your network.

##### Communications from the Websites

We may use your email address to send our newsletters and/or marketing communications. If you no longer wish to receive these communications, you can opt out by following the instructions contained in the emails you receive or by contacting us at [support@freshdesk.com](mailto:support@freshdesk.com).

We will send you announcements related to the Service(s) on occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our Service(s) is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email. Generally, you may not opt-out of communications which are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive them, you may deactivate your Account.

##### Advertising

We partner with third-party advertising networks to either display advertising on our Websites or to manage our advertising on other websites. Our ad network partner may use cookies and Web beacons to collect information about your activities on our Website and other websites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests (this will only be the case if we have your consent in certain locations).

##### Protection of Information

The Websites and Service(s) have industry standard security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. When you provide us with sensitive information (such as credit card information or login credentials), we will encrypt that information via Secure Socket Layer (SSL).

While there is no such thing as “perfect security” on the Internet, we take all reasonable steps to ensure the safety of your personal information. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our Websites or via the Service(s) and any transmission is at your own risk. Once we receive your personal information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

Additionally, you retain all rights of ownership to your personal data we collect. Except as set forth herein under sections elaborating on use of your personal information above and legal disclosure below we will not sell or share your personal data with any third parties or use your personal data to compete with you. Your privacy and the privacy of your customers are of utmost importance to us. If you have questions about our security you can contact us at [support@freshdesk.com](mailto:support@freshdesk.com).

##### Testimonials

We post customer testimonials/comments/reviews on our Websites which may contain personal information. Prior to posting the testimonial, we obtain the customer's consent to post their name along with their testimonial. If you want your testimonial removed, please contact us at [support@freshdesk.com](mailto:support@freshdesk.com). If you, as a customer of Our Service, Glowboard, wish to publish on your websites, any testimonials you have received from third parties via e-mails or widgets, it is your responsibility to obtain consent from such third parties prior to publishing the testimonials. You understand that We will not be liable to any person for unauthorized publishing of testimonials by customers of Glowboard.

##### Corrections and Updates

Upon request Freshdesk will provide you with information about whether we hold, or process on behalf of a third party, any of your personal information. To request this information please contact us at [support@freshdesk.com](mailto:support@freshdesk.com).

We allow users of the Service(s) or Website to access, update or modify their information by clicking on the My Account link in the Freshdesk navigation menu or by contacting us at [support@freshdesk.com](mailto:support@freshdesk.com). We seek to respond to requests for access or modification as soon as possible and within reasonable timeframe.

##### Children's Personal Information

Freshdesk does not knowingly collect any personal information from children under the age of 13. If you are under the age of 13, please do not submit any personal information through our Websites or Service(s). We encourage parents and legal guardians to monitor their children’s Internet usage and to help enforce this Policy by instructing their children never to provide personal information through our Service(s) or Websites without their permission. If you have reason to believe that a child under the age of 13 has provided personal information to us through our Websites or Service(s), please contact us and we will endeavor to delete that information and terminate the child's account from our databases.

##### Amendments

Amendments to this Policy will be posted to this URL and will be effective when posted. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Website prior to the change becoming effective. Provided we will not be notifying you if we amend the Policy to make addition, deletions or modifications to the list of cookies from time to time to keep the list of cookies current and accurate. You should frequently visit this Policy to check for amendments. Your continued use of this Websites or the Service(s) following the posting of any amendment, modification, or change to this Policy shall constitute your acceptance of the amendments to this Policy. You can choose to discontinue use of the Websites or Service(s), if you do not accept the terms of this Policy, or any modified version of this Policy.

##### Legal Disclosure

We reserve the right to disclose your personal data as required by applicable law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or other legal process served on us. Your personal data will also be shared between our Group Companies for the activities permitted under this Policy.

In the event Freshdesk goes through a business transition, such as a merger or acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your user account and personal data will likely be among the assets transferred. You will be notified via [support@freshdesk.com](mailto:support@freshdesk.com) and via a prominent notice on our Websites of any such change in ownership or control. We may also disclose your personal information to any other third party with your prior consent.

##### Contacting Freshdesk

If you have any questions about this privacy policy or your dealings with the Freshdesk, you can contact us at [support@freshdesk.com](mailto:support@freshdesk.com) or via postal mail at Freshdesk, Inc. 1250 Bayhill Drive, Suite 315, San Bruno, CA 94066.
